<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ChipDefense</string>
    <string name="button_startGame">Start new game</string>
    <string name="pref_filename" translatable="false">prefs.xml</string>
    <string name="button_resume">Resume</string>
    <string name="failed">Failed to clear stage.</string>
    <string name="success">All stages cleared!</string>
    <string name="cleared">Stage cleared.</string>
    <string name="last_stage">Last stage was: %d</string>
    <string name="win">You win.</string>
    <string name="next_stage">Next stage: %d</string>
    <string name="coins_gathered">Coins gathered: %d.</string>
    <string name="game_start">Starting game.</string>
    <string name="continue_game">Enter</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_inf">Inf</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_waves">Wave</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_status">Status</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_coins">Coins</string>
    <string name="selectLevel">Select Level</string>
    <string name="play_selected_level">Play selected level</string>
    <string name="button_marketplace">Heroes</string>
    <string name="button_refund">Reset all</string>
    <string name="button_purchase">Hire</string>
    <string name="level_entry">Level %d</string>
    <string name="level_selector">Level Selector</string>
    <string name="query_reset">Do you want to reset all heroes?</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>

    <string name="instr_1">
"Your computer is being invaded by an evil virus. Rogue code fragments - shown as Ones and Zeroes - try to get through to the cpu.

Tap on the empty slot to add a chip as defense against the attack, and then tap again to confirm your choice.

The most basic chip is 'SUB 1' which subtracts 1 from the attacker's value: 1's become 0's, and 0's disappear and are no longer a threat."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_2">
"You may also tap on an attacker. This will invert its value: 1 becomes 0, and 0 becomes 1.

Inverting a 0 will actually make the attacker more dangerous, so be careful not to tap on everything you see."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_3">
"The currency in this game is information. It is displayed on the bottom left.

Destroy the attacking code to gain some information about the virus. Use it to buy additional chips or to upgrade the existing ones."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_4">
"Here are some hints:

Remember that in binary,
  10 equals 2,
  11 equals 3,
100 equals 4,
and so on.

Try to tap on numbers starting with '1'. This reduces the attacker's number and makes the level much easier.  Any attacker that gets through to the CPU will cost one life, regardless of its number. You must have at least one SUB chip to get rid of them.      "</string>
    <string name="instr_5">
"In the next level, a new chip type is available. It is labelled 'SHR 1', which means 'shift right by 1'

All digits are moved one position to the right. The leftmost digit is replaced by 0.

For example, 0110 becomes 0011. This is equivalent to dividing the value by 2."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_6">
"By clearing stages, you can gain cryptocoins. These coins are valuable. You can use them to hire some
powerful Heroes of the Information Age who will give you significant advantages in the game.

There is a maximum amount of cryptocoins per level shown on the bottom, and each life lost will reduce the reward.

If you do not get all the coins, you can always replay the level. However, once you have obtained the maximum, you won't receive any more coins for this stage.
"
    </string>
    <string name="instr_7">
"Sometimes you will see a cryptocoin moving along with the attackers. You can collect it by destroying it, even multiple times when you replay the level.

But be careful. The moving cryptocoin is stronger than ordinary attackers, and if it reaches the CPU, it will take one of your lives."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_8">
"You can sell existing chips and re-use their slot. Most, but not all of the information will be refunded."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_9">
"Let's introduce another chip. The MEM (for memory) chip takes a number and stores it safely away in memory.

MEM chips are powerful because they can take out any attacker, but they are very slow."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_10">
"The accumulator chip (ACC) is a bit more complex than the others, but it can be very effective against large numbers of attackers. It takes two numbers and combines them into one result.

In its basic variant, it adds the two numbers. If you upgrade the chip once, it will OR the input numbers. Upgrading twice makes the operation an AND.

Example: If the numbers 0110 (that is 6) and 0011 (that is 3) enter the ACC chip, the result will be
1001 (that is 9) when adding [ACC +]
0111 (that is 7) using OR [ACC v]
0010 (that is 2) using AND [ACC &amp;].

The advantage of ACC is that it is really fast."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_11">
"Larger numbers are represented in hexadecimal. They are shown with a leading 'x'.

In hex, you have digits from 0 to 9 and then from A to F. The hex number 0x0F equals 15, or 1111 in binary."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_12">
"Two more chip types: ADD and SHL.\n\nThese do the opposite of SUB and SHR, respectively: They add 1 to the number and shift the bits to the left.\n\nOf course, this is really undesired. You can 'upgrade' these chips to reduce their strength or make them disappear."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_13">
"Note that cryptocoins are unaffected by ACC and also by MEM chips."
    </string>

    <string name="turing">
"Alan Turing was one of the most important persons in computer science. He created many of the foundations in theoretical computing, such as the Turing machine and the Turing test, but he is also famous for cracking the Enigma code in World War 2. His impact on the outcome of the war can hardly be overestimated.

He was heavily discriminated against because of his homosexuality. He died, probably by his own hand, in 1954."
    </string>
    <string name="lovelace">
"Ada, Countess of Lovelace is held to have invented the concept of Programming.

Together with Charles Babbage she worked on his mechanical calculation machine. She created an instruction set for the calculation of Bernoulli numbers, which is probably the first formal program ever written.

Lovelace realized that the abilities of a programmable engine were much greater than arithmetical computations. She also was the first to distinguish the symbolic concepts (software) from the physical parts (hardware).

She died in 1852, aged only 36."
    </string>
    <string name="hollerith">
"Data storage and processing started when Herman Hollerith introduced punched cards. He developed and merchandised a punched card tabulating machine to assist in collecting, sorting, and summarizing information. It was used (among other uses) for census purposes in many countries.

In 1896, Hollerith founded the Tabulating Machine Company that should later become International Business Machines (IBM)."
    </string>
    <string name="osborne">
"In 1981 Adam Osborne created the first portable computer. The 'Osborne 1' was not really what we nowadays call a laptop, it was more like a big suitcase with a weight of over 11 kg. However, it had everything a computer needed in one compact case: Power supply, keyboard, two floppy drives, a CRT monitor, and lots of software.

Osborne was also an author and book publisher."
    </string>
    <string name="cernettes">
"Les Horribles Cernettes, or LHC, are the High Energy Rock Band of the European research facility CERN. They also were The First Band On The Web.

After Berners-Lee had invented the World Wide Web, he was looking for some content to put into it. Silvano de Gennaro provided him with a photo of the Cernettes taken in july 1992, which became the first photo of a band that appeared in browser windows all over the world."
    </string>
    <string name="knuth">" Donald Ervin Knuth is a computer scientist and mathematician who has made numerous contributions to theoretical computer science.  He is mostly known for the monumental work 'The Art of Computer Programming', a project that started in 1962 and is still not finished. For this he created en passant the TeX formatting system that has become the standard for scientific publications all over the world.     "</string>
    <string name="zuse">
"The first modern computer was built by Konrad Zuse in 1941. The Z1 was a programmable, electro-mechanical machine that operated on a digital base, implemented Boolean logic, and even used floating point numbers.

Zuse also created the first high-level programming language 'Plankalkül'."
    </string>
    <string name="franke">
"Herbert W. Franke was a physicist well known as an author of science fiction novels and documentary works.

He was a pionieer in the field of computer art and computer graphics, and developed the concept of 'cybernetical aesthetics' - art created by electronic devices and numerical algorithms."
    </string>
    <string name="vaughan">
"Dorothy Vaughan was one of the 'human computers' working with the NASA. She was capable of solving complex mathematical equations faster and more reliably than the electronic or mechanical devices available at the time. With other women, she significantly helped advancing the American space program.

Later, as manager at the NASA, she prepared for the introduction of electronic computers by teaching herself and her staff the FORTRAN programming language."
    </string>
    <string name="tramiel">
"As a child, Idek Tramielski survived Auschwitz. In 1947, he emigrated to the USA, where in 1954 he founded Commodore International, a company manufacturing typewriters. In 1982, Commodore presented the C64, the world's first real home computer.

The record-selling C64 not only had an enormous 64 kiB of RAM, it also featured hi-res graphics, digital sound, a built-in BASIC interpreter, and two joystick ports. Countless persons made their first steps into the information age on good old C64."
    </string>
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="settings_about">About</string>
    <string name="license">\n        \nThis game is open source. Visit https://github.com/ochadenas/cpudefense for more information.\n\nThe portraits of the Information Age Heroes are mostly derived from works of the public domain.\n\nOriginal photos:\n  Alex Handy (CC BY-SA 2.0)\n  Jacob Appelbaum (CC BY-SA 2.5)\n  Rama (CC BY-SA 2.0 fr)\n  Shervinafshar (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Tony Bove (CC BY 3.0)\n  Wolfgang Hunscher (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Silvano de Gennaro (courtesy of the author)\n\nComputer boards:\n  Autopilot (CC BY-SA 4.0)\n  Bill Bertram (CC-BY 2.0)\n  Oliver Chadenas (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Smial (FAL)\n\nAll other artwork:\n  Oliver Chadenas (CC BY-SA 3.0)</string>
    <string name="play_level_x">Play level %d</string>
    <string name="button_exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_SUB">SUB chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_startinfo">Starting information</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_SHR">SHR chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_ACC">ACC chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_MEM">MEM chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_upgrade">Chip upgrade cost</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_lives">Additional lives</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_frequency">Attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_att_speed">Attacker speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_info_gain">Information gain</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_refund">Refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="upgrade_format">%s  [cost: %d]</string>
    <string name="toast_next_stage">Stage %d</string>
    <string name="toast_stage_cleared">Stage cleared</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CHIPSPEED">Increases speed of all %s chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_STARTINFO">Increases information at start of level</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_UPGRADECOST">Decreases upgrade cost of all chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_LIVES">Grants additional lives</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_FREQUENCY">Decreases attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_INFOOVERTIME">Gains additional bits over time</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ATTSPEED">Decreases attacker speed</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_REFUNDPRICE">Increases refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="toast_loading">Loading ...</string>


</resources>