<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ChipDefense</string>
    <string name="button_startGame">Start new game</string>
    <string name="quit">Quit</string>
    <string name="pref_filename" translatable="false">prefs.xml</string>
    <string name="pref_filename_level_structure" translatable="false">structure</string>
    <string name="pref_filename_savegames" translatable="false">saves</string>
    <string name="pref_filename_state" translatable="false">state</string>
    <string name="button_resume">Resume game</string>
    <string name="button_playlevel">Play stage</string>
    <string name="button_nextlevel">Play next stage</string>
    <string name="failed">Failed to clear stage.</string>
    <string name="success">All stages cleared!</string>
    <string name="cleared">Stage cleared.</string>
    <string name="last_stage">Last stage was: %d</string>
    <string name="win">You win.</string>
    <string name="next_stage">Next stage: %d</string>
    <string name="coins_gathered">Coins gathered: %d.</string>
    <string name="game_start">Starting game.</string>
    <string name="enter_game">Enter</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_inf">Inf</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_waves">Wave</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_status">Status</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_coins">Coins</string>
    <string name="selectLevel">Select Level</string>
    <string name="play_selected_level">Play selected level</string>
    <string name="button_marketplace">Heroes</string>
    <string name="button_refund_all">Reset all</string>
    <string name="button_refund_one">Fire</string>
    <string name="button_purchase">Hire [1 coin] </string>
    <string name="button_purchase_plural">Hire [%d coins]</string>
    <string name="cost_desc">[cost: %d]</string>
    <string name="level_entry">Level %d</string>
    <string name="level_selector">Level Selector</string>
    <string name="query_reset">Do you want to reset all heroes?</string>
    <string name="query_restart_game">Really start a new game? This will reset all your progress.</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>

    <string name="instr_1">
"Your computer is being invaded by an evil virus. Rogue code fragments - shown as Ones and Zeroes - try to get through to the cpu.

Tap on the empty slot to add a chip as defense against the attack, and then tap again to confirm your choice.

The most basic chip is 'SUB 1' which subtracts 1 from the attacker's value. It turns 1's into 0's, and it makes 0's disappear. Only then they are no longer a threat."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_2">
"You may also tap on an attacker. This will invert its value: 1 becomes 0, and 0 becomes 1.

Inverting a 0 will actually make the attacker more dangerous, so be careful not to tap on everything you see."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_3">
"The currency in this game is information. It is displayed on the bottom left.

Destroy the attacking code to gain some information about the virus. Use it to buy additional chips or to upgrade the existing ones."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_4">
"Here are some hints:

Remember that in binary,
  10 equals 2,
  11 equals 3,
100 equals 4,
and so on.

Try to tap on numbers starting with '1'. This reduces the attacker's number and makes the level much easier.

Any attacker that gets through to the CPU will cost one life, regardless of its number. You must have at least one SUB chip to get rid of them.      "</string>
    <string name="instr_5">
"In the next level, a new chip type is available. It is labelled 'SHR 1', which means 'shift right by 1'

All digits are moved one position to the right. The leftmost digit is replaced by 0.

For example, 0110 becomes 0011. This is equivalent to dividing the value by 2."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_6">
"By clearing stages, you can gain cryptocoins. These coins are valuable. You can use them to hire some powerful Heroes of the Information Age who will give you significant advantages in the game.

There is a maximum amount of cryptocoins per level shown on the bottom, and each life lost will reduce the reward.

If you do not get all the coins, you can always replay the level. However, once you have obtained the maximum, you won't receive any more coins for this stage.
"
    </string>
    <string name="instr_7">
"Sometimes you will see a cryptocoin moving along with the attackers. You can collect it by destroying it, even multiple times when you replay the level.

But be careful. The moving cryptocoin is stronger than ordinary attackers, and if it reaches the CPU, it will take one of your lives."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_7a">Chips need to cool down between operations. Hire heroes to reduce the chance of grouped attackers overwhelming a chip.\n\nIf you are stuck, you can replay a lower level trying to catch a running cryptocoin.\n</string>
    <string name="instr_8">"\nYou can sell existing chips and re-use their slot. Most, but not all of the information will be refunded.\n\nNote that an activated chip will complete its current cooldown cycle before disappearing. "</string>
    <string name="instr_9">"\nLet's introduce another chip. The MEM (for memory) chip takes a number and stores it safely away in memory. A little white indicator shows that there is a value inside.\n\nThe MEM chip must be 'read out' (by tapping on it). Once you have tapped on the chip, its cool down cycle starts, and only after that the memory slot becomes available again. A thick white frame indicates whether you should tap on the chip.\n\nFor now, the MEM chip can hold only one attacker,. Later in the game you will be able to buy upgrades, creating additional slots.\n\nMEM chips are powerful because they can take out any attacker, but they require your attention, and they are quite slow.\n\n    "</string>
    <string name="instr_10">
"The accumulator chip (ACC) is a bit more complex than the others, but it can be very effective against large numbers of attackers. It takes two numbers and combines them into one result.

In its basic variant, it adds the two numbers. If you upgrade the chip once, it will OR the input numbers. Upgrading twice makes the operation an AND.

Example: If the numbers 0110 (that is 6) and 0011 (that is 3) enter the ACC chip, the result will be
1001 (that is 9) when adding [ACC +]
0111 (that is 7) using OR [ACC v]
0010 (that is 2) using AND [ACC &amp;].

The advantage of ACC is that it is really fast."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_11">
"Larger numbers are represented in hexadecimal. They are shown with a leading 'x'.

In hex, you have digits from 0 to 9 and then from A to F. The hex number 0x0F equals 15, or 1111 in binary."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_12">
"Two more chip types: ADD and SHL.\n\nThese do the opposite of SUB and SHR, respectively: They add 1 to the number and shift the bits to the left.\n\nOf course, this is really undesired. You can 'upgrade' these chips to reduce their strength or make them disappear."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_13">
"Note that cryptocoins are unaffected by ACC and also by MEM chips."
    </string>
    <string name="instr_14">Another chip becomes available! \n\nThe CLK (clock) chip does not affect the attackers itself. Instead, it speeds up the other chips on the board. Each time the CLK ticks, the cooldown timer of all other chips is reset, and they become ready to operate anew.\n\nUpgrading increases the CLK frequency.</string>
    <string name="instr_15">Overclocking the CPU can be dangerous: The faster your chips work, the hotter they will get.\n\nEach time your clock resets a chip, a small amount of heat is produced. Temperatures of more than %d degrees can damage the CPU, that means, that they can cost you one life.</string>
    <string name="instr_16">The NOP chip (No operation) does nothing. But since it occupies a slot, you might want to remove it.\n\nA NOP 2 chip also does nothing, but twice.</string>
    <string name="instr_17">Two more undesired chip types, then we have seen them all.\n\nDUP duplicates an attacking piece of code. Instead of one attacker, you\'ll have two, with the same number.\n\nSPLT (split) does nearly the same, but instead of simply duplicating the number, it splits it into two pieces. For example, xA4 becomes xA0 and x04. This is somewhat the opposite of ACC: If the two resulting numbers are combined by logical OR, you\'ll get the original values. \n</string>
    <string name="instr_18">Beware! Sneak attack!</string>
    <string name="instr_22">Remember that SHR chips are powerful but cannot eliminate attackers. They quickly reduce large values, but against hordes of weak attackers, multiple SUB chips may be a more cost-effective defence.</string>
    <string name="instr_23">Not all electronic components are logic chips. There are also important classic, analogue components such as capacitors [C] or resistors [R]. \n\nIn this game, resistors have the effect of slowing down the attackers for a certain period of time. Their strength is indicated by three coloured rings. The slowing effect is the bigger the stronger the attackers are. One-bit-numbers are hardly affected at all, whereas 8-bit numbers become quite slow by large resistances.\n\nResistors generate heat. There is a hero (Claude Shannon) who can convert some of this heat into information.\n</string>
    <string name="instr_endless">You have successfully cleared all stages and won the game!\n\nIf you want, you can continue in \"endless\" mode, with randomly generated circuits that get more and more difficult. You will start the \"endless\" series without heroes, and you cannot use the coins gathered until now. \n\nHow far will you get?</string>


    <string name="turing">
"Alan Turing was one of the most important persons in computer science. He created many of the foundations in theoretical computing, such as the Turing machine and the Turing test, but he is also famous for cracking the Enigma code in World War 2. His impact on the outcome of the war can hardly be overestimated.

He was heavily discriminated against because of his homosexuality. He died, probably by his own hand, in 1954."
    </string>
    <string name="lovelace">
"Ada, Countess of Lovelace is held to have invented the concept of Programming.

Together with Charles Babbage she worked on his mechanical calculation machine. She created an instruction set for the calculation of Bernoulli numbers, which is probably the first formal program ever written.

Lovelace realized that the abilities of a programmable engine were much greater than arithmetical computations. She also was the first to distinguish the symbolic concepts (software) from the physical parts (hardware).

She died in 1852, aged only 36."
    </string>
    <string name="hollerith">
"Data storage and processing started when Herman Hollerith introduced punched cards. He developed and merchandised a punched card tabulating machine to assist in collecting, sorting, and summarizing information. It was used (among other uses) for census purposes in many countries.

In 1896, Hollerith founded the Tabulating Machine Company that should later become International Business Machines (IBM)."
    </string>
    <string name="osborne">
"In 1981 Adam Osborne created the first portable computer. The 'Osborne 1' was not really what we nowadays call a laptop, it was more like a big suitcase with a weight of over 11 kg. However, it had everything a computer needed in one compact case: Power supply, keyboard, two floppy drives, a CRT monitor, and lots of software.

Osborne was also an author and book publisher."
    </string>
    <string name="cernettes">
"Les Horribles Cernettes, or LHC, are the High Energy Rock Band of the European research facility CERN. They also were The First Band On The Web.

After Berners-Lee had invented the World Wide Web, he was looking for some content to put into it. Silvano de Gennaro provided him with a photo of the Cernettes taken in july 1992, which became the first photo of a band that appeared in browser windows all over the world."
    </string>
    <string name="knuth">" Donald Ervin Knuth is a computer scientist and mathematician who has made numerous contributions to theoretical computer science.  He is mostly known for the monumental work 'The Art of Computer Programming', a project that started in 1962 and is still not finished. For this he created en passant the TeX formatting system that has become the standard for scientific publications all over the world.     "</string>
    <string name="zuse">
"The first modern computer was built by Konrad Zuse in 1941. The Z1 was a programmable, electro-mechanical machine that operated on a digital base, implemented Boolean logic, and even used floating point numbers.

Zuse also created the first high-level programming language 'Plankalkül'."
    </string>
    <string name="franke">
"Herbert W. Franke was a physicist well known as an author of science fiction novels and documentary works.

He was a pionier in the field of computer art and computer graphics, and developed the concept of 'cybernetical aesthetics' - art created by electronic devices and numerical algorithms."
    </string>
    <string name="vaughan">
"Dorothy Vaughan was one of the 'human computers' working with the NASA. She was capable of solving complex mathematical equations faster and more reliably than the electronic or mechanical devices available at the time. With other women, she significantly helped advancing the American space program.

Later, as manager at the NASA, she prepared for the introduction of electronic computers by teaching herself and her staff the FORTRAN programming language."
    </string>
    <string name="tramiel">
"As a child, Idek Tramielski survived Auschwitz. In 1947, he emigrated to the USA, where in 1954 he founded Commodore International, a company manufacturing typewriters. In 1982, Commodore presented the C64, the world's first real home computer.

The record-selling C64 not only had an enormous 64 kiB of RAM, it also featured hi-res graphics, digital sound, a built-in BASIC interpreter, and two joystick ports. Countless persons made their first steps into the information age on good old C64."
    </string>
    <string name="wiener">"Norbert Wiener is known as the founder of cybernetics, i.e. the control and regulation of machines, and is thus one of the pioneers of artificial intelligence. The term 'cyber' coined by him is ubiquitous today.  \n\nHe developed mathematical theories, especially in the field of pattern recognition and image processing, and proved a number of mathematical theorems.  \n\nDue to his experiences in WW2, he adopted an increasingly pacifist stance and refused to publish works that might cause harm in the hands of militarists.\n   "</string>
    <string name="pascal">
"Blaise Pascal was a polymath in many fields of mathematics, philosophy and physics. For the later information age, his calculating machines, the \'Pascalines\', were an early precursor.

The programming language Pascal is named after him."</string>
    <string name="hopper">"\nGrace Brewster Murray Hopper had the idea that computer programs could be written in human-readable language instead of as sequences of Ones and Zeroes. She designed the FLOW-MATIC programming language, and thus invented the first compiler.\n    "</string>
    <string name="mandelbrot">Benoît Mandelbrot was the most important founder of fractal geometry, which can not only be used to describe many structures in nature very well, but also to create fantastic graphics on the computer. \n\nThe graphical representation of the Mandelbrot set went viral and founded a new age of computer art.</string>
    <string name="schneier">"Bruce Schneier is an expert on cryptography and information security. He has written important books on the subject, most notably 'Applied Cryptography', and has designed several cryptographic algorithms.\n        \nHe is not afraid of criticizing governments or global companies if he deems their actions counterproductive to security or violating the right of privacy.\n "</string>
    <string name="meier">Sidney K. Meier has created some of the most influential strategy games and revolutionised the genre. With comparatively simple rules, his games simulate the complexities of reality amazingly well. And they always tell a story: of the age of the railways, of the American Revolution, or - as in his most famous work \'Civilization\' - of 6000 years of human history.</string>
    <string name="kilby">Jack St. Clair Kilby had the idea of combining semiconductor elements - such as transistors or diodes - in an integrated circuit (IC) instead of wiring the components individually on a board. This was the basis for microchips and processors and made modern electronics with its miniaturisation possible in the first place.\n\n\nJack Kilby is also regarded as co-inventor of the pocket calculator and thermal printer.</string>
    <string name="chappe">Together with his four brothers Ignace, Pierre François, René and Abraham, Claude Chappe developed the optical telegraph. His \"tachygraph\" was the first system with which information could be transmitted quickly over long distances, making it the forerunner of all modern communication. Around 1830, the Chappe semaphore system connected Paris with many important cities in France and Europe.</string>
    <string name="hamilton">As a young programmer, Margaret Elaine Hamilton worked on military projects. In the mid-1960s she joined the Apollo moon landing project and quickly became head of software development. She and her team were responsible for programming and testing the guidance computer on board the spacecraft and lunar module, with the astronauts\' lives depending on the absolute reliability of the programmes.\n\nHamilton coined the term software engineering. And she is available as a Lego figure.\n</string>
    <string name="leibniz">Like Pascal, Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz was also a great polymath of his time. We owe to him important advances in numerous very different fields of science, which are far too numerous to list here.\n\nHis achievement for the information age is the construction of complex mechanical calculating machines, which can be seen as the forerunners of modern computers. Above all, however, he recognised the importance of the dual system and the binary number code, which all digital devices use today.</string>
    <string name="ohm">Georg Simon Ohm was one of the first to attempt to describe electrical processes mathematically. His work initially attracted little attention and was dismissed as an academic gimmick. It was not until Charles Wheatstone recognised their importance and asked Ada Lovelace to translate some of Ohm\'s works into English.\n\nToday, his name is inextricably linked with electrical resistance. Ohm\'s law and the unit of resistance are named after him.\n</string>
    <string name="volta">Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta was an experimental physicist who questioned and refuted some of the theories and assumptions prevailing at the time. He not only discovered the gas methane, but also made groundbreaking discoveries in the new field of electricity. He described the relationship between voltage, charge and capacity. Above all, however, he developed the first functioning battery. \n\nThe unit of electrical voltage, the volt, is named after him.\n</string>
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="about_title">About</string>
    <string name="about_version">Version %s.</string>
    <string name="about_license">"This game is open source. Visit <a href="https://github.com/ochadenas/cpudefense#MIT-1-ov-file">github.com/ochadenas/cpudefense</a> for more information.\n\nThe portraits of the Information Age Heroes are mostly derived from works of the public domain.\n\nOriginal photos:\n  Alex Handy (CC BY-SA 2.0)\n  Jacob Appelbaum (CC BY-SA 2.5)\n  Konrad Jacobs (CC BY-SA 2.0 de)\n  Rama (CC BY-SA 2.0 fr)\n  Shervinafshar (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Tony Bove (CC BY 3.0)\n  Wolfgang Hunscher (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Silvano de Gennaro (courtesy of the author)\n  Clermont Auvergne Métropole (CC BY-SA 4.0)\n  Jean-Frédéric (CC BY 2.0)\n  Tekniska Museet (CC BY 2.0)\n  The Royal Society (CC BY-SA 4.0)\n  Tanyakh (CC BY-SA 4.0)\n\nComputer boards:\n  Autopilot (CC BY-SA 4.0)\n  Bill Bertram (CC-BY 2.0)\n  Oliver Chadenas (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  Smial (FAL)\n\nAll other artwork:\n  Oliver Chadenas (CC BY-SA 3.0)\n  "</string>
    <string name="about_info_title">Info</string>
    <string name="about_info_text">For additional info and hints on game play visit the game\'s wiki on the web.</string>
    <string name="play_level_x">Play level %d</string>
    <string name="link_wiki">Game Wiki</string>
    <string name="button_exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="button_retry">Retry</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_SUB">SUB chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_startinfo">Starting information</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_info_on_kill">Additional info</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_SHR">SHR chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_ACC">ACC chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_MEM">MEM chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_RES">Resistance value</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_duration">R effect duration</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_heat">Generated heat</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_upgrade">Chip upgrade cost</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_lives">Additional lives</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_frequency">Attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_att_speed">Attacker speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_att_strength">Attacker strength</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_coin_strength">Coin strength</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_info_gain">Information gain</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_heat_conversion">heat converted</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_double_chance">%s double hit chance</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_range">%s chip range</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_refund">Refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_max_hero_upgrade">Max hero level</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_limit_unwanted">Unwanted chip count</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_reduce_removal">Chip removal cost</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_enable_mem_upgrade">MEM max. level</string>
    <string name="upgrade_format">%s  [cost: %d]</string>
    <string name="stage_number">Stage %d</string>
    <string name="toast_stage_cleared">Stage cleared</string>
    <string name="toast_enter_stage">Stage %d</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CHIPSPEED">Decreases cooldown time of all %s chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_HEAT">Reduces the amount of generated heat</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_STARTINFO">Increases information at start of level</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_UPGRADECOST">Reduces upgrade cost of all chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_LIVES">Grants additional lives</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_FREQUENCY">Decreases attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_INFOOVERTIME">Gains additional bits over time</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ATTSPEED">Reduces attacker speed</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_COINSTRENGTH">Reduces cryptocoin strength</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ATTSTRENGTH">Reduces attacker strength</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_MAXHEROUPGRADE">Increases maximal upgrade level of other heroes</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_REFUNDPRICE">Increases refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_GAININFO">Increases information gain through destroying attackers</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RANGE">Increases %s chip range</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_LIMITUNWANTED">Reduces the number of unwanted chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_DECREASEREMOVAL">Reduces the cost of unwanted chip removal</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ENABLEMEM">Enables upgrading of MEM chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RES_STRENGTH">Increases the strength of resistors</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RES_DURATION">Increases the duration of resistance effect</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CONVERT_HEAT">Converts some of the resistors\' heat into info</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CHANCE_DOUBLE">Gives %s chips a chance of double effect</string>
    <string name="toast_loading">Loading …</string>
    <string name="name_series_1">Normal</string>
    <string name="name_series_2">Turbo</string>
    <string name="name_series_3">Endless</string>
    <string name="message_series_unavailable">Complete all levels in \'normal\' mode first.</string>
    <string name="message_endless_unavailable">Available after completing all previous levels.</string>
    <string name="stage_reached">Stage reached: %s %d</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_2">You may replay all levels</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_3">in \'turbo\' mode now.</string>
    <string name="instr_2_1">
"In turbo mode, the attackers are stronger, faster and more numerous.

Furthermore, some slots are already taken by unwanted chips you'll have to deal with."</string>
    <string name="settings_disable_background">Disable background</string>
    <string name="settings_show_atts_in_range">Show attackers in range</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_1">" "</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_4">" "</string>
    <string name="query_quit">Do you want to quit the current stage?</string>
    <string name="button_return_to_main_menu">Return to main menu</string>
    <string name="continue_game">Continue playing</string>
    <string name="buttton_replay">Replay stage</string>
    <string name="settings_use_large_buttons">Use large objects</string>
    <string name="settings_show_framerate">Show frame rate</string>
    <string name="button_back">Close</string>
    <string name="button_info">Info</string>
    <string name="button_releasenotes">Release Notes</string>
    <string name="text_about">About …</string>
    <string name="instr_did_you_know">Did you know?</string>
    <string name="settings_keep_levels">Keep created stages in \'endless\' mode</string>
    <string name="settings_fast_fast_forward">Use really fast forward</string>
    <string name="game_paused">GAME PAUSED</string>
    <string name="overheat">CPU damage from overheating</string>
    <string-array name="fun_fact">
        <item>Until 1999, the amount of 1024 B was called a <i>kilobyte</i> (kB). For consistency with other SI units, the kilobyte\'s meaning was changed to 1 kB = 1000 B. To keep the former definition, the kibibyte was invented, with 1 KiB = 1024 B.</item>
        <item>An actual computer bug was found in a Harvard Mark II computer in 1947. A small insect had gotten into a relay, making programs fail.\n\nThe term \"bug\" for computer errors, however, had been used well before. Already in the 19th century small defects in mechanical devices were called bugs.</item>
        <item>\"Bread bin\" (or \"breadbox\") was a nickname for the Commodore C64, due to its characteristic and not very elegant form.</item>
        <item>In the 1980s, a hole punch was an important tool for computer users, as it allowed the storage capacity of a floppy disc to be doubled.\n\nThe writable side of a floppy disc was determined by the drive using a notch in the cover. If a hole was carefully punched in the opposite side, the disc could be turned over and used from the back.</item>
        <item>If you want to know how a computer actually works, have a look at the excellent site <b>NANDgame.com</b>.\n\nThere, you can build a programmable machine starting only with electric relays. You will find many familiar components, such as ADD or SHR.</item>
        <item>The very first computer adventure game "ADVENT" was developed by William Crowther, who was also a passionate speleologist (a cave explorer).\n\nThe \"Colossal Cave\" from the game really exists, albeit unfortunately without dragons, dwarfs, or treasures.</item>
        <item>There are 10 types of people in this world: Those who understand binary, and those who don\'t.\n\n\n(Old programmers\' joke.)</item>
        <item>In the "Tales of Pirx the Pilot" by Stanisław Lem, the spaceship "Ariel" crashes on Mars during its landing approach. It turns out that the on-board computer was suffering from a kind of obsessive-compulsive disorder. The more critical the situation became, the more information it requested in its control mania until it could no longer process the amount of data.\n\nA similar situation occurred in reality during the first moon landing. Fortunately for the astronauts, however, the on-board computer was programmed by Margaret Hamilton and her team in such a way that it simply stopped performing less important tasks under stress. Thus it remained operational, and the \"Eagle\" landed safely on the moon.</item>
        <item>The development of storage capacity over a period of around 60 years is astonishing: a punch card (surface area approx. 156 cm²) has a storage capacity of 80 bytes. A standard microSD memory card today with a surface area of approx. 1.65 cm² and only slightly thicker has a capacity of 256 GB.\n\nThat is a ratio of approx. 1 : 300,000,000,000.\n\nHowever, the back of the punch card can be used to take notes, or write a shopping list. This is not possible with the memory card.</item>
        <item>The keyboard of an IBM 3270 terminal was so sturdy and heavy that some say that it could be used to beat stupid users to death with it.\n\nOthers claim that they have actually done so.</item>
        <item>In the ASCII character set, which we know today as ISO-8859, there are still reminders of its origins as a telegraph alphabet. For example, the ASCII code 07 ("BEL") is used to ring a small bell on a teletypewriter.</item>
        <item>Long before the invention of the touchscreen, there was the light pen. This pen-shaped device was connected to the computer by a cable and could determine its position on the screen. To do this, it had a light-sensitive photocell at its tip.\n\nIn CRT monitors, the electron beam creates the image line by line. By measuring the exact time of the light flash perceived by the pen, the current position of the beam and thus also of the pen could be determined.\n\nThe light pen became obsolete by computer mice, and the principle does not work with modern flat screens anyway.</item>
        <item>In the 1990s, the programme \'xsnow\' was very popular on Unix computers. It made snowflakes gently fall down on the desktop background, building heaps on the top of the programme windows. From time to time the flakes were swirled by the wind, and sometimes you could see Santa Claus flying across the screen in a reindeer sleigh. The -showrudolph option determined whether the foremost reindeer had a red nose.</item>
        <item>Snacks are good in moderation.\n\n\n(“Tip of the day” in Civilization IV)</item>
        <item>To subtract one number from another in the binary system, you don\'t need to know how to subtract. Instead, you invert the number, add 1 and add the result.\n\nWhy does this work? If you invert a number - for example 0101 1110 (x5E) into 1010 0001 (xA1) - and add the two together, you always get 1111 1111 (i.e. xFF). Add 1 and discard the carry, this will yield 0000 0000. You can therefore interpret the number xA2 (i.e. xA1 plus 1) as "minus x5E". Example: x7F - x5E is x21, and 0x7F + xA2 (shortened to 8 bits) is also x21.</item>
        <item>A \"pizza box\" is a flat computer housing shape with a square form. The term was coined in the 1990s for the SPARC workstations from Sun Microsystems with their elegant shapes that actually look like a pizza box.</item>
        <item>Douglas Engelbart is said to have invented the computer mouse. Although this is true, he was not the first. Almost exactly at the same time as Engelbart\'s first demo, the Telefunken company commercially launched a mouse with a roller ball. However, at a price of DM 1500, this was reserved for a few specialised users, such as universities.</item>
        <item>Probably the best-known chip of all times is the 7400 by Texas Instruments, which only contained four NAND gates. The 74xx series provides basic logic functions. It is not only extremely popular with hobbyists, but is also widely used in the commercial sector. The newer 74xx and 74xxx chips now contain highly complex circuits, but the oldest types still exist virtually unchanged.</item>
        <item>The first hackers in history were Lois Blanc and his twin brother François, who also developed modern roulette. The Blanc brothers used the Chappe telegraph to transmit information from the Paris stock exchange, which they used for insider trading and made considerable profits. They skilfully used a special character of the Chappe alphabet with the meaning \"delete previous character\" to hide their information in regular messages. They were convicted in 1836, but not sentenced as there was no law that they had broken.</item>
        <item>It is unworthy of excellent men to lose hours like slaves in the labour of calculation which could safely be relegated to anyone else if machines were used.\n\nGottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, 1685</item>
        <item>An \"ultimate machine\" has the only purpose to switch off itself. It is often realized as a box with a switch or a lever on it to activate the machine. This will make an arm come out of the box to switch the lever off again.\n\nA famous creator of Ultimate Machines was Claude Shannon together with his student Marvin Minsky. Other \"useless machines\" were designed already in the 1930s by Bruno Munari.</item>
        <item>Hewlett-Packard was one of the first companies to bring programmable pocket calculators onto the market. They used \"Reverse Polish Notation\", which took some getting used to at first, but allows quick and compact calculation instructions.\n\nHP calculators were also known for their solid and high-quality workmanship. Some of them are still in use today, and even some calculations for ChipDefense were carried out on an HP 11C (built in 1985).</item>
        <item>The earliest programmable pocket calculators were intended for use for serious engineering calculations, but also some games were published for them. For example, there was "Lunar Lander".\n\nThe calculator would display the height and vertical speed of a lunar module, and the player had to enter the amount of fuel to be burned in the rockets. If you used too few, the lander would eventually crash into the surface; if you used too much, it would run out of fuel and also crash. In this case, the display showed the number 3507. Turned upside down, this reads LOSE.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="ZZ_message_of_the_day">There have been major changes to game play, especially on the \"Endless\" levels. Check out the Release Notes in the INFO screen.</string>
    <string name="ZZ_release_notes">Release Notes\n\nVersion 1.42\n============\nNew features:\n- Stage number is displayed on the game screen\n\nBug fixes:\n- Fixed some problems when selecting heroes for leave\n- Fixed \"heat to cash\" conversion calculation for resistors\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- The required \"shortest path length\" in endless mode has been raised for stage numbers > 200 \n\nVersion 1.41\n============\nBug fixes:\n- Fixed some problems when returning after switching apps\n- Better loading and scaling of background images\n- Margaret Hamilton must not appear before stage 24.\n- Some text corrections\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Massively reduced the number of waves for higher stages in Endless mode\n- Resistors now act simultaneously on all targets in range.\n- Slightly changed the screen size of several game element\n\nVersion 1.40\n============\nNew features:\n- New heroes: Claude Shannon, George Boole, Whit Diffie\n- Resistors now produce heat, which can be converted into information if Shannon is available.\n- Some more \"Did you know\" messages.\n\nBug fixes:\n- Avoid a situation where the player must choose a hero, but none is displayed.\n- Heroes always went on leave for three levels, regardless of what the text said.\n- The game uses a default system font if the desired font is not available. This had led to crashes on some devices.\n\nVersion 1.39\n============\nNew features:\n- Starting with \"endless\" stage 16, heroes may go on holiday. The player must choose one of several proposed heroes and grant leave to one of them.\n\nBug fixes:\n- Attackers that were slowed down by resistors behaved weird in ACC and MEM chips.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- The slowing effect of resistors now depend on the attacker\'s value. The stronger the attacker, the more it gets slowed.\n\nVersion 1.38\n============\nNew features:\n- The attackers held in the internal register of MEM and ACC are now released when selling the chip. \n\nBug fixes:\n- Game elements as well as hired heroes became active only when the stage was played a second time.\n- MEM and ACC chips are no longer \"emptied\" when resuming the app.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Removed the SELL option in stage 6\n \nVersion 1.37\n============\nBug fixes:\n- Fixed some bugs that occurred when re-entering the application.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Use of a custom font for chips and code fragments.\n\nVersion 1.36\n============\nNew functions:\n- New chip type: Resistors\n- Level 32 added\n- New heroes: Georg Ohm, Alessandro Volta\n\nBug fixes:\n- The level indicator on the welcome screen was limited to 99.\n\nVersion 1.35\n============\nBug fixes:\n- Fixed an occasional game crash when there were lots of attackers.   \n- Leibniz is no longer affected by Sid Meier.\n- MEM chips are no longer sold instantly. \n\nVersion 1.34\n============\nIMPORTANT: The \"Endless\" level series now has its own CryptoCoins and a separate set of heroes. The existing coins have been distributed proportionally. Under certain circumstances, the heroes had to be reset; in this case, the coins have been credited to you and you will have to hire the heroes again.\nThe difficulty of the Endless levels has been drastically reduced in compensation.\n\nNew functions:\n- New hero: Gottfried Leibniz.\n\nBug fixes:\n- There were no CryptoCoins for level 30.\n- ACC chips showed more than one slot, although they can only hold one value.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Tramiel is limited to level 5 now.\n- Upgrade of MEM chips is significantly more expensive and requires Leibniz.\n\nVersion 1.33\n============\n    Two more levels were added, introducing SPLT and DUP.\n    Heroes now can be downgraded individually.\n    MEM chips can be upgraded (up to level 4) to hold more than one value. An explanatory text was added to stage 14.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n    Chips now target cryptocoins first.\n    \nVersion 1.32\n============\nNew Features:\n    New hero added: Margaret Hamilton\n\nBugfixes:\n    Level selection in \"endless\" series was limited.\n    Two MEM chips could swallow the same attacker simultaneously.\n\nVersion 1.31\n============\nNew Features:\n    Two more types of \"negative\" chips: DUP and SPLT\n    (an introductory level with explanation will be added later).\n\nBugfixes:\n    Number of negative chips in \"endless\" stages reduced.\n    Revised the calculation of stage difficulty in endless stages.\n    Isolated slots are avoided, paths have a minimum length.  \n\nMiscellaneous:\n    Removal cost of negative chips depend on how many have already been removed.\n    \nVersion 1.30\n============\nNew Features:\n- new hero: Claude Chappe\n- Clearer design for buying and selling chips\n- Chips now choose their target intelligently (with more than one attacker in range)\n- Added an easter egg.\n\nBugfixes:\n- No new \"endless\" stages were available in the level selector beyond level 28.\n- Heat generation and damage corrected and adjusted\n- Fixed yet another bug when resuming the game\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Changes in \"endless\" stage generation. Difficulty of the stage layout increases with the level. Impossible configurations are avoided.\n- Changed the order of some levels in \"normal\" mode to make the difficulty progress more consistently.\n\nVersion 1.29\n============\nNew Features:\n- New design for welcome screen. Moved \"start new game\" to \"settings\". Added Release Notes in \"info\" section.\n- Revised generation of levels in \"endless\" series and made these levels clearer. Multiple CPUs are now possible.\n\nBugfixes:\n- Attackers were accelerated too much in ACC chips\n- Correction of speed control button size\n- Scrolling hero list was too slow\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- IMPORTANT: MEM chips must now be cleared \"by hand\" (by tapping on them) before they can absorb next attackers.\n\nVersion 1.28\n============\nNew Features:\n- New endless level series\n- In the About screen, added links for accessing the game wiki and the license on the Internet.\n- Chips are not removed instantly after being sold. Instead, they complete their current cooldown.\n\nBugfixes:\n- The game crashed when trying to display kiB values\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- decreased overall attacker frequency\n- slightly increased Mandelbrot\'s effect\n- Attackers now have their speed slightly altered by ACC chips\n- several adjustments to game play\n\nVersion 1.27\n============\nNew Features:\n- Chips can be bought and sold even when game is paused.\n- Introduction of heat. Overheating may result in loss of one life.\n- Temperature sensor added to score board.\n- New chip type: NOP\n- New hero: Jack Kilby\n\nBugfixes:\n- Passing coins do no longer activate MEM chips.\n- Chip type is shown on description of range-extending heroes.\n- Text on Hire button did not change on purchase or reset.\n- Score board layout improved.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Re-organization of preferences / saved games file\n- Changed the way how game speed is handled\n\nVersion 1.26\n============\nNew Features:\n- new settings and about dialog\n- hero biography is now scrollable\n- added button to lock scrolling of the game viewport\n\nBugfixes:\n- fixed a bug that led to loss of heroes in version 1.25.\n  Added correction code to refund coins lost due to this bug.\n- chip sell prices were not converted to B or kiB\n- SHR 9 (and higher) chips had no effect\n- attackers stopped appearing when pausing the game between two waves\n- corrected delay between waves in fast forward mode\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- stage 8 made easier\n- LEDs now go out instead of turning red\n\nVersion 1.25\n============\nNew Features:\n- Chips can be bought and sold even when game is paused.\n- Introduction of heat. Overheating may result in loss of one life.\n- Temperature sensor added to score board.\n- New chip type: NOP\n- New hero: Jack Kilby\n\nBugfixes:\n- Passing coins do no longer activate MEM chips.\n- Chip type is shown on description of range-extending heroes.\n- Text on Hire button did not change on purchase or reset.\n- Score board layout improved.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Re-organization of preferences / saved games file\n- Changed the way how game speed is handled\n\n\nVersion 1.24\n============\nNew Features:\n- new background pictures\n- hero costs are shown on the \'hire\' button\n- overall small graphical improvements\n\nBugfixes:\n- game stays in portrait mode, keeps the device awake\n- corrected coin count and size of attackers when resuming game\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- replaced Android system style dialogs by custom design\n\nVersion 1.22\n============\nNew Features:\n- Chips can be bought and sold even when game is paused.\n- Introduction of heat. Overheating may result in loss of one life.\n- Temperature sensor added to score board.\n- New chip type: NOP\n- New hero: Jack Kilby\n\nBugfixes:\n- Passing coins do no longer activate MEM chips.\n- Chip type is shown on description of range-extending heroes.\n- Text on Hire button did not change on purchase or reset.\n- Score board layout improved.\n\nMiscellaneous:\n- Re-organization of preferences / saved games file\n- Changed the way how game speed is handled\n</string>
    <string name="message_cannot_fire">Use \'%s\' to release this hero.</string>
    <string name="message_is_on_leave">%s is currently on leave.</string>
    <string name="instr_leave">Some heroes are asking for time off. You must grant leave to one of them, who will return after %d levels.</string>
    <string name="instr_leave_1">Some heroes are asking for time off. You must grant leave to one of them, who will return in the next level.</string>
    <string name="heroes_on_leave_0">No heroes are on leave.</string>
    <string name="heroes_on_leave_1">Hero on leave:</string>
    <string name="heroes_on_leave_2">Heroes on leave:</string>
    <string name="shannon">Claude Elwood Shannon is considered the founder of information theory and one of the fathers of the information age. One of his major achievements was to transfer the mathematical theory of Boolean algebra to real circuits, thereby making modern digital computers possible. \n\nShannon developed the concept of information and entropy in messages, made important contributions to cryptography, and worked on artificial intelligence. Among other things, he described a programme for playing chess and constructed a mechanical mouse that could find its own way through a maze.  \n</string>
    <string name="boole">The achievement of George Boole Jr. lies in the fact that he formalised the concepts of logic and thus made them part of mathematics. Boolean algebra is the basis for the internal functioning of all modern computers.\n\nBoole was the son of a shoemaker and never attended any school other than primary school. He taught himself maths, Latin and Greek, French and German.</string>
    <string name="diffie">Together with Martin Hellmann, Bailey Whitfield Diffie developed the DH key exchange between two parties named after the two of them. They thus created an essential prerequisite for secure connections over the Internet.\n\nDiffie is also concerned about social issues of cryptography. He is a staunch advocate of the right to privacy.</string>
</resources>